Guide to the Jazz Loft Project Records, 1950-2012 and undated RL.10001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Oral Histories, 1991-2010; 614 items
  - Konitz, Lee, 2000 September 14; Archival Resource Key; 51
    In this oral history, Konitz discusses the atmosphere at the Jazz Loft, including memories of other musicians who played there like Bob Brookmeyer and Jimmy Raney. Konitz also talks about attending composition classes led by Hall Overton at Juilliard and Overton's reputation within the jazz community.
    - Lee Konitz, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Lee Konitz, 9-14-00, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2000 September 14 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0068)
    - Lee Konitz, 9-14-00, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2000 September 14 (Box 26, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0066)
  - Lawson, Janet, 2003 October 30; Archival Resource Key; 52
    Janet Lawson (b 1940) was born in Baltimore, MD into a family of professional musicians. She studied under Hall Overton, was a jazz vocalist until 2002, and teaches as an adjunct faculty member in New York City.
    In this oral history, Lawson talks about her professional career and how Hall Overton helped her develop her musical skills. In particular, Lawson discusses moving to New York City, becoming involved with the jazz community, and taking lessons with Overton at the Jazz Loft.
    - Janet Lawson Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Janet Lawson, 10/30/03, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2003 October 30 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0069)
    - Janet Lawson, 10/30/03, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2003 October 30 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0070)
    - Janet Lawson, 10/30/03, w/Sam Stephenson, I/2, II/2 starts, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2003 October 30 (Box 26, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0067)
    - Janet Lawson, 10/30/03, II cont'd, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2003 October 30 (Box 26, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0068)
  - Listengart, Phil, 2004 November 09; Archival Resource Key; 53
    Phil Listengart is a sculptor and educator who is also the cousin of multi-instrumentalist and Jazz Loft contributor Eddie Listengart.
    In this oral history, Listengart discusses the development of his own art practice and the troubled life of his cousin, jazz musician Eddie Listengart.
    - Phil Listengart, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Phil Listengart, 11-9-04, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 November 09 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0071)
    - Phil Listengard, 11-9-04, 1/2, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 November 09 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0061)
    - Phil Listengard, 2/2, 11-9-04, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 November 09 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0062)
  - Massters, Joey, 2005 June 27; Archival Resource Key; 54
    Joseph Mastercusio, better known as Joey Massters (1925-2007) was born in Boston, MA, and died in Bellingham, WA. He was a jazz pianist and participated in many loft jam sessions in the late 1950s and early 1960s.
    - Joe Massters, 6-27-05, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 June 27; 64 minutes (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0072)
    - Joe Massters, 6-27-05, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 June 27; 53 minutes (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0073)
    - Joe/Joey Masters, 6.27.05, I, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 June 27 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0063)
    - Joey Massters, 6-27-05, II of 3, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 June 27 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0064)
    - Joey Masters, III of 3, 6-27-05, ~ 5 min. long, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 June 27 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0065)
    - Joe Massters, I, 6/27/05, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 June 27 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0069)
    - Joe Massters, I & II, 6/27/05, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 June 27 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0070)
  - McClure, Ron, 2004 September 14; Archival Resource Key; 55
    Ron McClure (b. 1941) was born in New Haven, CT. He learned to play bass in high school and had a successful professional career. He studied composition and arranging with Hall Overton in the mid-1960s.
    In this oral history, McClure talks about his development as a musician and his life as a jazz musician in New York City. McClure goes into detail about his interactions with Hall Overton, his memories of the Jazz Loft building, and his work as a musician with Blood, Sweat & Tears.
    - Ron McClure Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Ron McClure, 9-14-04, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 September 14 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0074)
    - Ron McClure, 9-14-04, (See DAT for Volume), Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 September 14 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0066)
    - Ron McClure, NYC, w/Sam, Dan, 9-14-04, 1/1, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2004 September 14 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0071)
  - Minor, Tom, 2005 May 11; Archival Resource Key; 56
    Tom Minor (b. 1942) was born in New York City. While studying photography at Princeton, Minor met Gene Smith through Bill Pierce. Minor assisted Smith making prints in his loft in the late 1960s. Minor became very involved with enviromental work later in life.
    In this oral history, Minor discusses his development as a photographer, his time spent working with W. Eugene Smith on various photographic projects, and his more current involvement with environmental and conservation issues.
    - Tom Minor Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Tom Minor, 5-11-05, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 May 11; 33 minutes (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0075)
    - Tom Minor, 5-11-05, I of I, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 May 11 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0067)
    - Tom Minor, 5-11-05, I of I Sold!; End portion of Harvey Overton I, ~ 5 min. or less, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 May 11 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0072)
  - Moore, Carman, 2004 August 10; Archival Resource Key; 58
    Carman Moore (b 1936) was born in Lorrain, OH. In 1958 he graduated from Ohio State University and moved to New York City to study composition with Hall Overton, with whom he became close friends.
    In this oral history, Moore discusses his early life, development as a musician and his life as a Juilliard student in New York City. In particular, Moore talks about his interactions with Hall Overton—taking lessons at the Jazz Loft, Overton's teaching style, and Overton's continuing influence.
    - Carman Moore Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Carman Moore, 8/10/04, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 August 10; 63 minutes (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0076)
    - Carman Moore, 8/10/04, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 August 10; 24 minutes (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0077)
    - Carman Moore, I, 8-10-04, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 August 10 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0068)
    - Carman Moore, II, ~30 min., 8-10-04, (NYC), Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 August 10 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0069)
    - Carman Moore, apt, 8/10/04, NYC, Sam, Dan, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2004 August 10 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0073)
    - Carman Moore, 2/2 (1st side only), 8/10/04, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2004 August 10 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0074)
  - Moran, Jason, 2007 August 27; Archival Resource Key; 59
    Jason Moran (b. 1975) is a jazz pianist and composer. In 2009, Moran produced "IN MY MIND," a multimedia performance investigating Thelonious Monk's 1959 recording, "Monk at Town Hall." The performance included audio of conversations between Monk and Hall Overton.
    In this oral history, Moran talks about the revelation of hearing W. Eugene Smith's recordings of Thelonious Monk, in particular the work sessions with Monk and Hall Overton as they prepared for the 1959 Town Hall concert. Moran discusses Monk's technical and artistic approach to creating music, his attitudes in person and in performances, and how the Town Hall concert was a radical experiment in jazz.
    - Jason Moran Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Jason Moran Interview by Sam Stephenson, 8/27/07, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2007 August 27; 20 minutes (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0078)
  - Morris, John, 2004 October 21; Archival Resource Key; 60
    John G. Morris (b. 1916) was born in Chicago. He is a legendary photography editor, having worked with LIFE Magazine and Robert Capa's work during World War II. Morris was a longtime friend and supporter of Smith, as well as the original executor of the Smith estate.
    - John Morris, Brown Bag, 10/21/04, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 October 21 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0079)
    - John Morris, Brown Bag, 10/21/04, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 October 21 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0080)
    - John Morris, CDS: Lunch Talk, 10/21/04, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 October 21 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0070)
    - John Morris, 10-21-04, Talk Cont'd, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 October 21 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0071)
    - John Morris, 10/22/04, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 October 22 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0081)
    - John Morris, 10/22/04, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2004 October 22 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0082)
    - John Morris, 1/2, 10-22-04, Interview @ CDS, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 October 22 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0072)
    - John G. Morris, 2/2, 10/22/04, Interview @ CDS, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2004 October 22 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0073)
    - John Morris, 10/22/04, I, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2004 October 22 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0075)
    - John Morris, 10/22/04, II (and end of I), Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2004 October 22 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0076)
    - John Morris, 9-29-09, CDS, int., Stephenson, Hart, Partridge present, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2009 September 29 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0074)
  - Neese, Al, 2001 July 05; Archival Resource Key; 61
    Al Neese was born in Greensboro, NC. A jazz trumpeter, he lived in New York City from 1951-1975, where he participated in many loft jam sessions with Freddie Redd, Dannie Richmond, and others in the early 1960s.
    In this oral history, Neese talks about growing up in North Carolina and moving to New York City in 1951 to pursue a life as a jazz musician. Neese lived on the Lower East Side, was involved with the jazz scene in the West Village, and spent a great deal of time at the Jazz Loft. Neese discusses W. Eugene Smith's surreptitious recording techniques, Thelonious Monk's work at the Jazz Loft, and other luminaries in the New York jazz community including Freddie Redd, Countess Pannonica de Koenigswarter.
    - Al Neese Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Al Neese, 7/5/01, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2001 July 05; 73 minutes (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0083)
    - Al Neese, 7/5/01, Part 1, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2001 July 05 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0077)
    - Al Neese, 7/5/01, Part 2, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2001 July 05 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0078)
  - Norris, Walter, 2003 October 02; Archival Resource Key; 62
    Walter Norris (1931-2011) was born in Little Rock, AK, and died at his home in Berlin, Germany. A jazz pianist, Norris participated in Jazz Loft jam sessions circa 1960. He also briefly lived next door at 823 Sixth Avenue. In 1977 he moved to Berlin to play with the Radio Free Berlin Orchestra.
    - Walter Norris, 10/2/03, I, Univ. AR, Little Rock, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2003 October 02 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0075)
    - Walter Norris, 10/2/28, II, Univ. AR, Little Rock, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2003 October 02 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0076)
    - Walter Norris, 10/3/03, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2003 October 03 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0084)
    - Walter Norris, 10/3/03, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2003 October 03 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0077)
    - Ark Hall of Fame, 10/3/03, Walter Norris, I, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2003 October 03 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0078)
    - Ark Hall of Fame, 10/03/03, Walter Norris, II, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2003 October 03 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0079)
  - Northern, Robert (Brother Ah), 2008 July 29; Archival Resource Key; 63
    Robert Northern (b 1934), known professionally as "Brother Ah," was born in Kinston, NC, and grew up in the Bronx. Northern played the French Horn in Thelonious Monk's 1959 Town Hall band which rehearsed in the loft with Hall Overton.
    In multiple interviews, Robert "Brother Ah" Northern discusses his family's background, including being forced to leave North Carolina after his father had an altercation with the Ku Klux Klan. He goes into detail about his musical development and his involvement with the jazz scene in New York. In particular, Northern talks about performing with Thelonious Monk at the Town Hall concert in 1959, Hall Overton's work as a composer and arranger, his own experience as an educator and performer, and his time spent in the Korean War.
    - Brother ah -- wash, dc, Rbt Northern, 7-29-08, DP, SS, Ah Sound-guy, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2008 July 29 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0080)
    - Brother Ah, 2/2, Wash, DC, R. Northern, 7-29-08, D.P., S.S., B.A. soundguy, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2008 July 29 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0081)
    - Robert Northern a.k.a. Brother Ah, 7/29/08, I, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2008 July 29 (Box 29, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0033)
    - Robert Northern, a.k.a. Brother Ah, 7/29/08, II, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2008 July 29 (Box 29, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0034)
  - Orensteen, Lou, 2000 December 01; Archival Resource Key; 64
    Lou Orensteen (b. 1932) was born in Hollywood, CA. As a tenor saxophonist, he participated in loft jam sessions in the late 1950s and early 1960s.
    In this oral history, Orensteen discusses his early life in California and Michigan, his time in the Korean War, and his involvement with various loft music scenes in New York City. Orensteen talks about jam sessions and musicians he frequently played with including Eric Dolphy, Sonny Clark, Jimmy Stephenson, and Tom Wayburn.
    - Lou Orensteen Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Lou Orensteen, 12/00, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2000 December 01 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0085)
    - Lou Orensteen, 12/00, Sam only, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2000 December 01 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0079)
    - Lou Orensteen, 12/00, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2000 December 01 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0080)
    - Lou Orensteen, cont'd, 12/00, ends early 1st side, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2000 December 01 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0081)
  - Overton, Dick, 2005 June 23; Archival Resource Key; 65
    Brother of Hall Overton.
    - Dick Overton, 6/23/05, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 June 23 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0086)
    - Dick Overton, 6/23/05, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2005 June 23 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0087)
    - Dick Overton, 6-23-05, 1/2, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 June 23 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0082)
    - Dick Overton, 6-23-05, 2/2, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2005 June 23 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0083)
    - Dick Overton, 6/23/05, I, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 June 23 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0082)
    - Dick Overton, 6/23/05, II, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2005 June 23 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0083)
  - Overton, Harvey, 2002 August 01; Archival Resource Key; 66
    Harvey Overton (b. 1921) was born in Bangor, MI, the second of the three Overton brothers. He was a writer and professor of humanities at Western Michigan University. Harvey visited his brother Hall Overton in the Jazz Loft.
    In multiple interviews, Overton talks about his childhood in Bangor, MI and the life and work of his brother, composer and musician Hall Overton. In particular, Harvey discusses Hall's early involvement with bands, his education in Chicago, and his eventual death from cirrhosis of the liver. Harvey also talks about his own career and the history of the Overton family.
    - Harvey Overton Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Harvey Overton, 3/12/02, I, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2002 March 12; 128 minutes (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0088)
    - Harvey Overton, 3/12/02, II, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2002 March 12; 14 minutes (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0089)
    - Harvey Overton, 8-1-02, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2002 August 01; 65 minutes (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0091)
    - Tom Minor, 5-11-05, I of I Sold!; End portion of Harvey Overton I, ~ 5 min. or less, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2002 August 01 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0072)
    - Harvey Overton, 8-1-02, Part 1, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2002 August 01 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0087)
    - Harvey Overton, 8-1-02, Part 2, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2002 August 01 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0088)
    - Harvey Overton, 3-12-02, I, cont'd on side B of next tape, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2002 March 12 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0084)
    - Harvey Overton, 3/12/02, "II" only tape w/sound, I cont'd on side B, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2002 March 12 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0085)
    - Harvey Overton, end of I, A & beginning of B, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2002 March 12 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0086)
    - Harvey Overton, I, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, undated (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0084)
    - Harvey Overton, II, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, undated (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0085)
  - Overton, Nancy, 2002 March 01; Archival Resource Key; 67
    Nancy Overton (1926-2009) was born Anne Swain in Port Washington, NY, and died in Blairstown, NJ. A vocalist, she was a member of the singing groups the Heathertones and Chordettes. She was married to Hall Overton.
    In multiple interviews, Overton talks about her life as a musician and her experiences as the wife of composer Hall F. Overton. She goes into great depth about Hall Overton's history in the Army, his teaching experiences, his relationship with W. Eugene Smith, and the health issues that lead to his death. Overton also talks about her family history with music, the development of her relationship with Hall Overton, and what it was like to spend time at the Jazz Loft.
    - Nancy Overton Transcripts, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Nancy Overton, 3/1/02, Harvey Overton, 3/12/02, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2002 March 01; 49 minutes (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0090)
    - Phil Woods, 1/15/02, Nancy Overton, 3/1/02, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2002 March 01 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0092)
    - Nancy Overton, 3/1/02, w/ Sam S., ends ~45 min, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2002 March 01 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0089)
    - Phil Woods, 1/15/02, Nancy Overton, 3/1/02, Part 1, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2002 March 01 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0137)
    - Phil Woods, 1/15/02, Nancy Overton, 3/1/02, Part 2, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2002 March 01 (Box 28, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0138)
  - Overton, Rick, undated; 68
    Rick Overton, younger brother of Hall Overton, goes into detail about his childhood in Bangor, MI and later life in California and Oregon. He also discusses the strong musical influences in the Overton family, which helped shape his brother's life as a composer and performer. Overton also talks about Hall's experiences in the war and early life in New York City.
    - Rick Overton Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Packard, Jean Cunningham, 2008 March 10; 69
    Jean Packard, formerly known as Jean Cunningham, was born in Los Angeles. A jazz pianist, she participated in Jazz Loft jam sessions in 1960.
    In this oral history, Packard talks about moving to NYC and becoming involved in the jazz scene. Other musicians like Bill Takas and Ronnie Bedford helped her get gigs and introduced her to Hall Overton, from whom she took music lessons. Packard also talks about leaving New York to play piano with a touring company of "Cabaret".
    - Jean Cunningham Packard, 3/10/08, Compact disc, Transcription copy, 2008 March 10 (Box 29, Audio-cd RL10001-CD-0035)
  - Partridge, Dan, 2008 March 24; 70
    Dan Partridge talks about his involvement with the Jazz Loft Project including his interest in Sam Stephenson's research about W. Eugene Smith and his experience listening to the Smith recordings. In particular, Partridge talks about the technical process of analyzing the recordings and the emergence of stories and relationships in the Jazz Loft narrative.
    - Margaret Hennessey, 4/30/2009 @CDS, Camera Tests, Dan Partridge @ CDS, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2008 March 24 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0090)
    - Dan Partridge Interview (cont.) @CDS, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2008 March 24 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0091)
  - Perkoff, Si, 2003 June 14; Archival Resource Key; 71
    Si Perkoff (b 1937) was born in St. Louis, MO. He started classical piano lessons when he was seven years old, and in 1957-58 he studied under Hall Overton at the loft.
    In this oral history, Perkoff talks about his development as a musician, including his early interest in boogie woogie music and how that lead to an education at California School of Fine Arts. Perkoff also goes into details about his time spent in New York City as a musician, as a student of Hall Overton, and his brief incarceration at Riker's for marijuana possession.
    - Simon Perkoff Transcript, 2002-2008 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Si Perkoff, I, 6/14/03, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2003 June 14; 61 minutes (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0093)
    - Si Perkoff, II, 6/14/03, Digital audio tape, Recorder original, 2003 June 14; 35 minutes (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL10001-DAT-0094)
    - Si Perkoff, I, 6/14/03, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2003 June 14 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0090)
    - Si Perkoff, II, 6/14/03, Mini-dv videocassette, Recorder original, 2003 June 14 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL10001-MDV-0091)
    - Si Perkoff, I, 6/14/03, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2003 June 14 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0092)
    - Si Perkoff, II, 6/14/03, Standard Audio-cassette, Transcription copy, 2003 June 14 (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL10001-CS-0093)
  - Pierce, Bill, 2004 September 14; Archival Resource Key; 72